Buvaneshkumar C

buvaneshkumar293@gmail.com | 9080980432

Professional Summary

2+ years of competence in IT services in the roles of a Software Engineer. Had good experience in all aspects of the SDLC from Conception, Design, and Development. Good communication with an emphasis on building client relationships. Having the ability to handle multiple tasks and work independently as well as in a team.

Experience

JUNIOR DEVELOPER - HEPL - A CAVINKARE GROUP | APRIL 2024 - PRESENT

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT - BASSURE SOLUTIONS | APRIL 2023 - SEPTEMBER 2023

TECHNICAL TRAINEE INTERN - BASSURE SOLUTIONS | OCTOBER 2023 - MARCH 2024

Education

B.E. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING | APRIL 2021 | IFET - ANNA UNIVERSITY

Skills

- · Java 8
- · Spring Boot
- · Docker
- · Git
- · Postman
- · Jenkins

- · React
- · Spring Microservices
- · MySQL, MongoDB
- · JMeter
- · RabbitMQ

Projects

FINTECH

TECH STACK- SPRING BOOT, REACT, MYSQL, SPRING CACHE

- This Fintech Application serves as a comprehensive platform designed to streamline the lending process by onboarding client banks, managing leads, facilitating loan applications, and providing real-time updates on loan statuses.
- It empowers various stakeholders, including sales managers, sales executives, and partners, while ensuring efficient loan processing and commission tracking with role-based access control feature.

LMS

TECH STACK- SPRING BOOT, SPRING MICROSERVICES, MONGODB, MYSOL, REACT

- This Learning Management System (LMS) is an application designed to streamline the process of onboarding educational organizations, generating assessments using AI, and managing the distribution and evaluation of tests.
- The platform leverages ChatGPT to generate test questions, supports exporting them to Excel and sending unique test links, and ensures secure test access for individual users.

TROVE

TECH STACK- SPRING BOOT, WEBSOCKET, MONGO DB, REACT, ZUSTAND, RABBITMQ

- Is a chat platform featuring private and group chat modules, integrated with an IDP (Identity Provider) service for secure user authentication and a Knowledge Management (KM) service where users can create and engage with posts, including liking posts within their organization.
- · A dedicated media processing module converts uploaded videos into multiple resolution formats using RabbitMQ for asynchronous processing and efficient task handling.
- Includes a survey module that allows organizations to create and manage surveys, enabling user participation and feedback collection.

OKR

TECH STACK- SPRING BOOT, MONGO DB, REACT

- The OKR system operates on a quarterly cycle, where organizational objectives are set by owners at the start of each quarter.
- These objectives are assigned to key stakeholders, who create quarterly child objectives and key results for their teams. Team members work on these objectives throughout the quarter, provide self-ratings upon completion, and managers evaluate their performance.
- Final ratings are consolidated at the end of the quarter to determine appraisals, including bonuses, promotions, and performance reviews.